

Profile

In a nutshell, I'm a mostly self-taught developer that breathes caffeine (I didn't learn to fall in love with what I do, it happened naturally as if it had already been planned).

I've been passionate about the programming universe since 2010. I don't limit myself to learning only part of it, but to learn as much as I can (I always preferred to know many things and not much about a few things).

I find myself full of desire to work with other people who strive and enjoy this area as much as I do.

Employment History

Founder at Caffeine Algorithm, Porto, Portugal

July 2016 — Present

A development organization that loves caffeine and algorithms which wants to help the largest number of people to know the programming universe, so that they can, acquire new knowledge and evolve even more.

Frontend Developer at InterNations GO!, Matosinhos, Portugal February 2019 — Present

A startup launched by InterNations in 2018 which combines all the essential relocation services in one place, making relocation a seamless process. Working with Vue, TypeScript, MobX, Cypress, SASS and Foundation.

Full Stack/Blockchain Developer at git//scale, Porto, Portugal August 2018 — December 2018

A code analytics platform aiming to take the Open Source model to the next level by adding an economic layer on top of the git protocol. Worked with React, Apollo, GraphQL, PostgreSQL, PostGraphile, SASS and Ant Design.

Frontend Developer at Weissmaler GmbH, Matosinhos, Portugal August 2017 — October 2018

A startup that simplified the painter search through reliability, quality and price. Worked on a dashboard for internal use with React, Relay, GraphQL, Flow, MobX, Cypress, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, PostGIS and Semantic UI.

Internships

Full Stack Developer at Netflow - Desenvolvimento de Sistemas de Informação, Lda, Porto, Portugal

March 2014 — August 2014

Integrated on a project to optimize the management of vending machines by creating a web application and also developing the features to control the Arduino/GSM board inside of each one.

Details

+351 913 416 022 contact@nelsonsilvadev.com

Date / Place of birth July 5, 1995 Póvoa de Varzim, Portugal

Nationality Portuguese

Links

nelsonsilvadev.com github.com/nelsonsilvadev caffeinealgorithm.com

Skills

JavaScript ES6 | React | Vue | Angular

CSS Preprocessors SASS | Styled Components

Unit and Functional Testing Jest | Cypress

Version Control System - Git

Module Bundler - Webpack

State Management - MobX

Tasks Automation - Gulp

A/B Testing - SiteSpect

Easily Adaptable

Teamwork

Languages

Portuguese

English

Hobbies

Writing, Reading, Cooking, Travelling, Exercising, Going Out

Education

Degree in Computer Science (EQF Level 6), Instituto Universitário da Maia - ISMAI, Maia, Portugal

2014 — 2017

Technological Specialization Course of Development of Information Systems (EQF Level 5), Instituto Universitário da Maia - ISMAI, Maia, Portugal

2013 - 2014

Y Extra-curricular activities

Speaker at Congresso Nacional de Profissionais de TI, Conapti, Brasil October 2016

"Know the course and the difficulties of a student that studies the programming area in Europe".

Projects

Eventdash

September 2016 — July 2017

A platform to increase the interactivity in relation to the given event and through the use of gamification.

Technologies: Ionic, Angular, TypeScript and Firebase.

Development: Last 4 Videos (each one between 2-5 hours) | Watch Trailer

Run For It

July 2016 — March 2017

An adventure game that I developed and that gave me more important notions for my learning according to the universe of game development, Google Play services and the market.

Technologies: Unity, Unity Ads, Google Play Games, C# and XML.

Development: First 14 Videos (each one between 2-5 hours) | Watch Trailer

Learn With The Robot (LWTR)

June 2015 — May 2016

An educational platform for kids to increase knowledge regarding school matters (6 different games for each grade).

Technologies: C#, XAML, SQLite and Entity Framework.

Human Blocks

October 2014 — April 2015

A survival game that I developed to understand game engines and that gave me important notions regarding the universe of game development.

Technologies: C#, XAML, SQLite and Entity Framework.